Guide to the New York Community Trust Records 1919-2024 MS 3246
New-York Historical Society
- Series 3: Historical materials (PARTIALLY RESTRICTED), 1919-2024
  - Sub-series 10: Photographs, 1953-2018
    - Photographs: Events, groups, portraits, 1953-2018 (Offsite-box 3.10.8, Folder 1-39)
      Folder 28: Pisani, Bernard
      Folder 29: Preiskel, Barbara Scott
      Folder 30: Robinson, Alexander L., Jr.
      Folder 31: Seymour, Whitney North
      Folder 32: Sidamon-Sristoff, Anne P.
      Folder 33: Slutsky, Lorie A.
      Folder 34: Stewart, Donald M.
      Folder 35: Trent, William T., Jr.
      Folder 36: Wainwright, Carroll L., Jr.
      Folder 37: Wang, Lulu
      Folder 38: West, Herbert B.
      Folder 39: Unidentified photographs
- Series 4: Program materials, ca. 1967-2023
  Series 4 contains papers, studies, reports, and strategies generated by the Program area of NYCT. Studies identifying and assessing needs in sectors such as education, arts and culture, jobs, housing, the environment, health, and social servies are found in this series. Reports by or commissioned by NYCT are included, as are grantmaking strategies developed by NYCT. Printed materials include brochures and booklets regarding NYCT grantmaking programs and activities.
  Materials are arranged chronologically. Series 4 is organized into 2 sub-series:
  4.1 Strategies, studies, reports, 1976-2023
  4.2 Printed materials, ca. 1967-2022, n.d.
  - Sub-series 1: Strategies, studies, reports, 1976-2023
    - Strategies, studies, reports, 1976-1996 (Offsite-box 4.1.1, Folder 1-18)
      Folder 1: A Discussion of the Possible Cash Flow Problems of Nonprofit Voluntary Agencies, January 1976 (NYCT Occasional Paper Series)
      Folder 2: Technical Assistance in New York City: A Preliminary Examination of the Nonprofit Technical Assistance Process, November 1976 (NYCT Occasional Paper Series)
      Folder 3: The New York City Fiscal Situation, April 1977 (NYCT Occasional Paper Series)
      Folder 4: The Economic Impact of the Blackout: The First 3 Weeks, August 1977 (NYCT Occasional Paper Series)
      Folder 5: Corporate Special Projects Fund, 1977-1992
      Folder 6: Housing in New York City: A Role for the New York Community Trust, October 1978 (NYCT Occasional Paper Series)
      Folder 7: List of New York Community Trust grant strategies, 1978-2012
      Folder 8: Health Care: A Strategy for Grantmaking, February 1979 (NYCT Occasional Paper Series)
      February 9: Survey of Arts-In-Education in New York City, April 1979 (NYCT Occasional Paper Series)
      Folder 10: Youth Issues and Services, December 1979 (NYCT Occasional Paper Series)
      Folder 11: Youth Services in New York City: A Role for the New York Community Trust, December 1979 (NYCT Occasional Paper Series)
      Folder 12: Youth Services Fund Priorities (NYCT), February 1980
      Folder 13: Handicapped Children: Issues and Services, October 1980 (NYCT Occasional Paper Series)
      Folder 14: Toward a Funding Strategy for Handicapped Children: A Role for the New York Community Trust, October 1980
      Folder 15: Toward a Focus for Mental Health Grants: New York Community Trust, December 1981
      Folder 16: Mental Health: Issues and Services, December 1981 (NYCT Occasional Paper Series)
      Folder 17: The Status of Girls and Women in New York City, February, April 1981
      Folder 18: Mary and David Hoar Fellowship Program for Research in Musculo-Skeletal Trauma, September 1981-April 1996
    - Strategies, studies, reports, 1982-2004 (Offsite-box 4.1.2, Folder 1-11)
      Folder 1: The Heiser Program for Research in Leprosy (an activity of the New York Community Trust), brochures and reports, 1982-2004
      Folder 2: An Evaluation of the New York Community Trust Housing Grants Program, by Michael A. Stegman and Anne Hafrey, April 1983
      Folder 3: New York Community Trust: Evaluation of Activities in the Field of the Elderly (draft), by Rose Dobrof (The Brookdale Center on Aging, Hunter College, CUNY), January 1984
      Folder 4: Recommended Guidelines for the Economic Development Grant Program, June 7, 1984
      Folder 5: Youth Employment in New York City: Recommendations for Grant Making Priorities, August 2, 1984
      Folder 6: Alzheimer's Disease (includes Seward Fund), September 1984-October 1990
      Folder 7: Issues and Services for Blind and Visually Handicapped Persons: A Role for the New York Community Trust, July 25, 1985
      Folder 8: Economic Development in New York City: A Review of Issues and Strategy for Grantmaking (NYCT Occasional Paper Series), September 1985
      Folder 9: Criminal Justice in New York City: Recommendations for Grantmaking Priorities, June 5, 1986
      Folder 10: The Status of AIDS in New York City, October 2, 1986
      Folder 11: Maxwell Pollack Award (to promote the concept of productive aging), October 1986-July 1993
    - Strategies, studies, reports, 1986-1988 (Offsite-box 4.1.3, Folder 1-21)
      Folder 1: Taking Care of Young and Old: The Common Stake, a report of the October 1986 policy symposium held at the New York Academy of Medicine, October 1986
      Folder 2: The Urban Environment of New York City: Recommendations for Grantmaking Policies, December 4, 1986
      Folder 3: Hispanics in New York City April 9, 1987, June 1999
      Folder 4: Public Education in New York City: A Review of Issues and Strategies for Grantmaking, (NYCT Occasional Paper Series), April 1987
      Folder 5: Developing an Outreach Strategy for Maramec Spring Park, June 4, 1987
      Folder 6: Legalization of Undocumented Immigrants in New York City, June 1987-August 1991
      Folder 7: Immigration in New York City: A Review of the Impact of the Immigration Reform Control Act of 1986, July 30, 1987, October 1996
      Folder 8: The Status of AIDS in New York City, September 1987 (NYCT Occasional Paper Series)
      Folder 9: Home Health Care Then and Now: An Investigation of the Intent of a Bequest, by Dorothy Levenson, Montefiore Medical Center, ca. 1987
      Folder 10: Historic Perspective on Our Grantmaking, February 4, 1988
      Folder 11: A Review of the 1987 Non-Advised Grant Program and Working Budget for 1988, February 4, 1988
      Folder 12: Report to the Trustees' Committee on the New York Community Trust, April 21, 1988
      Folder 13: The Status of Girls and Young Women in New York City: A Review of Grantmaking Priorities for the Girls & Women Program, June 2, 1988
      Folder 14: Issues of the Environment in New York 1988: A Strategy of Grantmaking to Make a Difference (NYCT Occasional Paper Series), June 1988
      Folder 15: David Warfield Fellowship Program in Ophthalmology, November 1988-October 1997
      Folder 16: New York Center for Policy on Aging (established by NYCT in 1985), mission statement; proposal for study, "Growing Older in New York City: A Study of Changing Lifestyles, Quality of Life, and Quality of Care," June 1988, 1990
      Folder 17: Our Summary of Peat Marwick's Recommendations of Marketing the New York Community Trust, July 28, 1988
      Folder 18: AIDS, Community Needs, and Private Funding: A Needs Assessment (prepared by the Planning Committee of the New York City AIDS Fund Advisory Committee), October 1988, (NYC AIDS Fund, a Special Project of NYCT)
      Folder 19: Intergenerational Programs in New York City: A Selected Listing of Representative Projects with Public Policy Significance (NYCT Occasional Paper Series), December 1988
      Folder 20: The Immigration Reform & Control Act of 1986: Making It Work (reprinted from 1988 NYCT Yearbook), 1988
      Folder 21: Report of the Not-For-Profit Energy Conservation Program (a partnership of the New York State Community Foundations and the State Energy Office), 1988
    - Strategies, studies, reports, 1989-1992 (Offsite-box 4.1.4, Folder 1-22)
      Folder 1: (Re: Drug Addiction) Brief of the New York Community Trust, Amicus Curiae, Docket no. 87-1294, January 12, 1989
      Folder 2: Community Foundations As Administrators of Restitution Funds, January 1989-January 1995
      Folder 3: The Substance Abuse Crisis in New York City: A Call to Action (briefing paper by Mathea Falco assisted by Interface for the NYCT), November 1989
      Folder 4: Substance Abuse Policy Discussion, December 7, 1989
      Folder 5: New York City AIDS Fund -- Grant recipients, 1989-1995
      Folder 6: A Neighborhood Revitalization Program that Works (reprinted from 1989 NYCT Yearbook), 1989
      Folder 7: Arts and Culture: Recommendations for Guidelines, April 5, 1990
      Folder 8: The Faces of New York's Homeless (reprinted from 1990 NYCT Yearbook), 1990
      Folder 9: A Partnership in Caring: A Blueprint for the Hunter College School of Social Work's Development until the Year 2000, ©1989, 1990 (project supported, in part, by NYCT)
      Folder 10: AIDS Community Needs and Private Funding: A Needs Assessment for New York City (1991 edition), February 1991
      Folder 11: New York City's Racial Elderly Population (NYCT Occasional Paper Series), February 1991 (New York Center for Policy on Aging, created by NYCT)
      Folder 12: The Funding Partnership for People with Disabilities -- Request for proposals, June 1991
      Folder 13: NYCT -- Guidelines for Grant Applicants, 1991, 2008, 2011
      Folder 14: NYCT priorities -- children, youth, families, 1991, 2004
      Folder 15: NYCT priorities -- community development and the environment, 1991, 2003, 2007
      Folder 16: NYCT priorities -- education, arts and the humanities, 1991, 1999
      Folder 17: NYCT priorities -- health and people with special needs, 1991, 2003, 2008
      Folder 18: The AIDS Crisis (reprinted from 1991 NYCT Yearbook), 1991
      Folder 19: A Report on Foundations' Support for Comprehensive Neighborhood-Based Community-Empowerment Initiatives by Arlene Eisen (funded in part by NYCT), March 1992
      Folder 20: Education Reform Proposals for Urban School Systems, August-October 1992
      Folder 21: NYCT -- Loan Guarantee Program, October 1992
      Folder 22: A Funder's Guide to AIDS Grantmaking: Action Strategies, 1992
    - Strategies, studies, reports, 1993-1998 (Offsite-box 4.1.5, Folder 1-17)
      Folder 1: NYCT Request for Proposal -- Cancer Research Projects, January 1993
      Folder 2: Growing Older In New York City in the 1990s: A Study of Changing Lifestyles, Quality of Life, and Quality of Care, vols. 1 and 2 (by New York Center for Policy on Aging of the NYCT), September 1993
      Folder 3: Growing Older In New York City in the 1990s: A Study of Changing Lifestyles, Quality of Life, and Quality of Care, vols. 3, 4, and 5 (by New York Center for Policy on Aging of the NYCT), September 1993
      Folder 4: Strengthening New York City Nonprofit Organizations: A Blueprint for Action (prepared for NYCT and United Way of NYC by The Conservation Company), ca. 1993
      Folder 5: A New York City Town Hall Meeting Final Report -- New York in the Clinton Years: Will Hope Reach the Big Apple? (a joint project of the Citizens Committee for New York City and The City Project with the NYCT and The New York City Partnership), January 1994
      Folder 6: Race and Intergroup Relations Initiative, July 1994(lb/> Folder 7: Agendas for Reform Proposals for Urban School Systems (report prepared by NYCT by Nancy M. Lederman), April 1995
      Folder 8: Education: Recommendations for Revised Guidelines, July 27, 1995
      Folder 9: Evaluation of the Park Homeless Outreach Project (report to NYCT which provided support), August 1995
      Folder 10: A Review of Grantmaking Priorities for the Social Services and Welfare Program, February 1, 1996
      Folder 11: A Review of Grantmaking Priorities for the Community Development Program, April 4, 1996
      Folder 12: A New Environmental Program, October 1, 1996
      Folder 13: Historic Preservation: A Role for the New York Community Trust, April 3, 1997
      Folder 14: The Henry Phillip Kraft Family Memorial Fund: A New Environmental Grantmaking Program for the New York Community Trust, October 9, 1997
      Folder 15: TSC Case Study: The New York Community Trust (technology upgrade at NYCT), ca. 1997
      Folder 16: Historic Preservation: A Role for the New York Community Trust, April 2, 1998
      Folder 17: New York City's Lesbian and Gay Community: An Overview of the Community and Its Needs, August 1998
    - Strategies, studies, reports, 1998-2004 (Offsite-box 4.1.6, Folder 1-22)
      Folder 1: Harvesting Our History: A Botanical and Cultural Guide to Queens' Chinese, Korean, and Latin American Communities (booklet supported in part by NYCT), 1998
      Folder 2: Rough Crossings: Family Caregivers' Odysseys Through the Health Care System (Special Report from United Hospital Fund, project supported by NYCT), 1998
      Folder 3: Revised Youth Development Grantmaking Strategy, February 1999
      Folder 4: The Edward and Sally Van Lier Fund, Assessment of Pre-College and Post-College Fellowship Programs, February 1999; Fund Evaluation Report, January 2016
      Folder 5: Restitution, April-May 1999
      Folder 6: A Guide Toward Better Jobs and Stronger Ties (The Neighborhood Strategies Project of NYCT), August 1999
      Folder 7: Brooklyn Legal Services Corporation A (supported by NYCT) Newsletter, Winter 1999
      Folder 8: New York Landmarks Conservancy's Emergency Preservation Grant Program (supported by NYCT), Newsletter, Winter 1999
      Folder 9: Hot Nights in the City: Global Warming, Sea-level Rise and the New York Metropolitan Region, ©1999 Environmental Defense Fund (study supported by NYCT)
      Folder 10: Making Health Care Decisions for Others: A Guide to Being a Health Care Proxy or Surrogate (project of Montefiore Medical Center, Division of Bioethics, funded in part by NYCT), 1999
      Folder 11: Hit or Miss: Fitness & Sports Opportunities in the New York City Public Schools, ©2000 (Project Director, Nancy M. Lederman, major funding for report by NYCT)
      Folder 12: The Highlands to Ocean Fund, brochure, ca. 2000
      Folder 13: Cool Solutions to Global Warning: 24 Success Stories from the Northeast, ©2001 Clean Air-Cool Planet (the work of Clean Air-Cool Planet was supported by a grant from the Kraft Fund)
      Folder 14: LoMap – Charting Lower Manhattan's Environment As Seen by Youth (project of the Green Map System, funded in part by NYCT), 2001
      Folder 15: World Resources Institute – safeclimate.net Website (a grant from NYCT supported the Website development), 2001
      Folder 16: Creating High Quality Inclusion Programs for Preschoolers with Disabilities in New York City: A Guide for Preschool Providers (written by Yvonne Rafferty, produced with support from Davis Polk and Wardwell Fund for Children in the NYCT), February 2002
      Folder 17: Lila Acheson Wallace Theatre Fund in Community Funds, Inc. – Program Guidelines, June 2002
      Folder 18: Revised Substance Abuse Grantmaking Strategy, April 2003
      Folder 19: Revised Grantmaking Strategy for the New York City Conservation and Environment Program, October 2, 2003
      Folder 20: A Revised Environmental Grantmaking Strategy for the Henry Phillip Kraft Family Memorial Fund, October 2, 2003
      Folder 21: Health Services, Systems and Policy: A Revised Grant Strategy, October 2004
      Folder 22: Adult Social Day Services: Is There a Future?, a scan and report to philanthropy by Markowitz Consulting for the New York Community Trust, November 2004
    - Strategies, studies, reports, 2005-2015 (Offsite-box 4.1.7, Folder 1-20)
      Folder 1: The State of the Arts and the State of Arts Funding: New York City by Mindy Duitz, Project Consultant, January 17, 2005
      Folder 2: Aging in the Shadows: Social Isolation Among Seniors in New York City (United Neighborhood Houses of New York Special Report, study supported by NYCT), Spring 2005
      Folder 3: A Grantmaking Strategy for Civic Affairs, July 2005
      Folder 4: Arts and Culture: Revised Grant Strategy for Civic Affairs, December 2005
      Folder 5: Smart Growth and the Challenges Facing the Trust, April 6, 2005
      Folder 6: State of the Arts (reports by Americans for the Arts), 2007-2009
      Folder 7: Education Program: A Revised Grant Strategy, December 2009
      Folder 8: Health Care and Jobs Initiative: NYC Workforce Funders, August 11, 2010
      Folder 9: A Grantmaking Strategy for the Social Work Profession: Improving Social Work Research, Education and Practice, December 1, 2011
      Folder 10: The New York Community Trust -- Report on the Francis Florio Fund: Research Program for Blood Disorders, ca. 2011
      Folder 11: Technical Assistance Program Grant Strategy, June 2012
      Folder 12: Proposal for Distribution of Astor Funds to Improve Education in New York City, June 19, 2012
      Folder 13: Community Development Program Grant Strategy, July 2012
      Folder 14: Training Today's Workers for Today's Jobs (NYC Workforce Development Fund in the NYCT), 2013
      Folder 15: Repairing the Ravages of Superstorm Sandy, Preparing for the Next Big One (NYCT brochure), 2013
      Folder 16: Revised Environmental Grantmaking Strategy for the Kraft Fund, April 3, 2014
      Folder 17: "Pablo Helguera: The Parable Conference," October 18, 2014, part of "Brooklyn Bred 2," curated by Martha Wilson, 2014 Next Wave Festival, Brooklyn Academy of Music, BAM Fisher, April 7-October 18, 2014
      Folder 18: Jobs and Workforce Development Grantmaking Strategy for New York City, June 5, 2014
      Folder 19: Human Justice Grantmaking Strategy, June 2015
      Folder 20: Making New York a Masterpiece (re: Edward and Sally Van Lier Fellowship for the Arts, reprint from NYCT 2015 Annual Report), 2015
    - Strategies, studies, reports, 2016-2022 (Offsite-box 4.1.8, Folder 1-17)
      Folder 1: Health and People with Special Needs: Context, Needs, and Opportunities for Grantmaking at the New York Community Trust, February 2016
      Folder 2: People with Special Needs Grantmaking Strategy, June 2016
      Folder 3: Health and Behavioral Health Grantmaking Strategy, June 2016
      Folder 4: Stronger Together: The Power of Funder Collaboration, 40 Years of Collaborative Funds in the New York Community Trust, August 2016
      Folder 5: Human Services Grantmaking Strategy for New York City, December 1, 2016
      Folder 6: Youth Development Grantmaking Strategy for New York City, December 1, 2016
      Folder 7: Technology Transforms Learning: HIVE Digital Media Learning Fund in the New York Community Trust, March 2017
      Folder 8: Welcoming the Newest New Yorkers: The Fund for New Citizens in the NYCT, March 2017
      Folder 9: A Report on the New York Community Trust Leadership Fellows Program at Baruch College, January 2019
      Folder 10: Power of Performance: An Analysis of the Giving Habits of Donors at New York's Community Foundation (2019 Philanthropic Trends Report, NYCT), 2019
      Folder 11: NYC COVID-19 Response & Impact Fund: A Briefing for the Steering Committee on the Grants Program, November 18, 2020
      Folder 12: Resilience & Resolve: NYC COVID-19 Response & Impact Fund Report (Fund Co-Chairs: Lorie Slutsky, NYCT and Darren Walker, Ford Foundation), January 2021
      Folder 13: New York State Census Equity in the New York Community Trust, Documentation & Evaluation Report (Seema Shah, Ph.D.), April 2021
      Folder 14: Healthy Lives, Promising Futures, Thriving Communities, Special Projects, Revolving Loan Fund (budgeted and approved grants), October 12, 2021
      Folder 15: Education Grantmaking Strategy, December 2021
      Folder 16: New York State Census Equity in the New York Community Trust, New York State Census 2020 Data Report (Seema Shah, Ph.D.), March 2022
      Folder 17: The State of American Philanthropy: Giving for Cancer Research, December 2022 (Irfan Hasan quoted, VP for Giving, NYCT)
  - Sub-series 2: Printed materials, ca. 1967-2022, undated
    - Printed materials, ca. 1967-2022, n.d. (Offsite-box 4.2.1, Folder 1-23)
      Folder 1: A Guide to Charitable Giving Through the New York Community Trust and Community Funds, Inc., ca. 1967-1971
      Folder 2: Handbook for Donor-Advisors: How to Use the Services of New York Community Trust and Community Funds, Inc. for Efficient Giving, ca. 1974
      Folder 3: Pocket Guide to Intelligent Giving: 22 Ways to Use the New York Community Trust, 1978, 1982, n.d.
      Folder 4: New York Community Trust/Community Funds, Inc. brochures, 1978, 1982, ca. 1998, n.d.
      Folder 5: Data on the New York Community Trust and Community Funds, Inc., ca. 1980
      Folder 6: A Handbook for the Donor-Advisor: How to Use the Services of New York Community Trust and Community Funds, Inc. for Efficient Giving, 1981-1982
      Folder 7: Handbook for Owners of Closely-held Businesses: How to Set Up a Charitable Foundation at Low Cost, August 1983
      Folder 8: Helping Corporations Manage Charitable Contributions, January 1986
      Folder 9: Helping Yourself As Well As Others: A Guide to Deferred Giving Programs, March 1986
      Folder 10: Understanding the New York Community Trust, November 1988
      Folder 11: The New York Community Trust -- Creating a Fund Here: Suggested Words and Procedurs, November 1988
      Folder 12: Smart Borrowing: A Nonprofit's Guide to Working with Banks by Edward Skloot, ©New York Community Trust, ca. 1989
      Folder 13: A Handbook for Donor-Advisors: How to Use Our Services for Rewarding and Efficient Giving, June 1990
      Folder 14: Creating a Fund Here: Suggested Words and Procedures, 1993
      Folder 15: A Guide to Making Your Philanthropic Wishes Come True, ca. 2007
      Folder 16: You Know That Good Feeling You Get When You Help Make Things Better?, September 2010
      Folder 17: Creating a Fund Here: Suggested Words and Procedures, n.d. (after 1980)
      Folder 18: Donor-advised funds brochures, 2016-2019, n.d.
      Folder 19: Guide to Giving: A How-To for Personal Philanthropy, 2017
      Folder 20: Power of Permanence: An Analysis of the Giving Habits at New York's Community Foundation, 2019 Philanthropic Trends Report, 2019
      Folder 21: Amplify Your Impact: How to Help Nonprofits Create Social Good Through Impact Investing, 2022
      Folder 22: A Handbook for Donor-Advisors, New York Community Trust/Long Island Community Foundation/Westchester Community Foundation, n.d.
      Folder 23: New York Community Trust Donor-Advisor Survey, n.d.
- Series 5: Media and marketing, 1923-2024
  Materials are arranged chronologically. Series 5 is organized into 5 sub-series as follows:
  5.1 Grants Newsletter, 1973-2024
  5.2 Professional Notes, 1991-2021
  5.3 Press releases, 1923-1960
  5.4 Press clippings, 1934-2024
  5.5 Advertisements and marketing, 1988-2024
  Series 5 contains two NYCT periodic publications, Grants Newsletter (1973-2023) and Professional Notes (1991-2021). Grants Newsletter provides news of NYCT grantmaking activities. Professional Notes provides information for tax and estate planning professionals. Press releases (1923-1960) are found in this series, as are press clippings (1934-2024). Also found in this series are print advertisements (1990-2022), publications reports, and marketing/communications planning.
  - Sub-series 1: Grants Newsletter, 1973-2024
    - Grants Newsletter, 1973-1991 (Offsite-box 5.1.1)
    - Grants Newsletter, 1992-2001 (Offsite-box 5.1.2)
    - Grants Newsletter, 2002-2011 (Offsite-box 5.1.3)
    - Grants Newsletter, 2012-2024 (Offsite-box 5.1.4)
      Includes Impact Report (2020-2023) and Spotlight (2019-2022)
  - Sub-series 2: Professional Notes, 1991-2021
    - Professional Notes, 1991-2009 (Offsite-box 5.2.1)
    - Professional Notes, 2010-2021 (Offsite-box 5.2.2)
  - Sub-series 3: Press releases, 1923-1960
    - NYCT press releases, 1923-1956 (Offsite-box 5.3.1)
    - NYCT press releases, 1957-1960 (Offsite-box 5.3.2)